本集拍摄过程  未伤及任何动物
No animals were harmed in the production of this episode
前情提要  "实习医生格蕾"
Previously on "Grey's Anatomy"...
主任被那个虚伪的疯子
The chief is under the spell
已经完全蛊惑了
of some insane man in camouflage.
欧文·亨特少校  我是战地外伤科医生
Major Owen Hunt.I'm a trauma surgeon.
你在阅读你母亲的日记
You're reading your mom's diary?
我连我老妈的一半都不如
I'm not half the surgeon my mother was.
主任要我们每人给乔治一个实习生
The chief wants us to give George one of our interns?
你从来就没想过要我
You didn't even think to ask for me?
去你的  欧麦利医生
Screw you, Dr. O'malley.
我们要不慢慢来  从一垒开始
We can take it slow. maybe just first base.
梅瑞狄斯
Meredith.
我只开这一个箱子
I'm only opening one box.
本来就不该打开任何箱子
The plan was not to open any.
我们只是要把你妈妈的箱子搬去阁楼
The plan was to take your mom's boxes up to the attic.
看啊  解剖了的简妮娃娃
Look. it's anatomy jane.
对于外科医生  每个病人都是战场
For a surgeon, every patient is a battle field.
我的书房看来是没戏了
I'll never have my own office.
他们是我们的地盘
They're our terrain,
我们在那里迂回侦测
Where we advance, retreat...
然后挖出所有的地雷
Try to remove all the land mines.
-她的  双胞肺  居然还在  -她的什么
-And she still has her little twosh. -her what?
这个娃娃有可拆卸的器官
Anatomy jane had detachable organs.
我以前老是记不住器官名  就干脆自己起名
I could never remember their real name, so I made up name
好比  双胞肺  就在  小胸膛  里
Like, the twosh was next to the chubbel,
那里正好连接着  小肝肝
And that was connected to the slivvy.
-看哪  这是  可爱的小尿袋  -尿袋  这名字好
-Oh, and look.it's the jelly pouch. -Jelly pouch. My favorite
但仍然搞不懂  为什么叫它  尿袋
Still can't get enough of the jelly pouch.
当你认为在战场上胜利而归时
And just when you think you've won the battle,
世界又恢复和平了
Made the world safe again...
随之又出现新的地雷
Along comes another land mine.
-我们还要跟其他人上床吗  -什么
-So are we screwing other people or not? -What?
我想知道  你是否准备就此离开
I just want to know if you're gonna go off
然后去玩弄欧麦利或其他的衰人
And screw O'malley or some other loser,
这样我就不用取消猎艳计划
Because then I don't have to cancel my plans
可以继续沾花惹草
With the chick from peds.
你这个混蛋
You're an ass.
什么
What?
真是不可思议
That was amazing
我也这么觉得
It was for me, too.
简直太难以置信了
I mean, that was amazing.
对啊
For me, too.
我这一生
My whole life...
成人以后  总是和男人在一起
My whole adult life, I have been with men.
我总觉得很不错  很好
And it always felt,you know, fine, good,
但我...从未...
But... I never...
我是指...真的..的确...
I mean--I mean, I did,but not...
从未如此美妙
Not like this.
我好象戴上了明目眼镜
This is like needing glasses.
我让你迷失方向了吗
Um, I've blinded you?
没有
No.
我小时侯  得了偏头痛
When I was a kid,I would get these headaches,
我去看医生
And I went to the doctor,
医生说  我需要戴眼镜
And they said that I needed glasses.
当时并不明白
I didn't understand that.
我能看见东西  为何要戴眼镜
It didn't make sense to me because I could see fine.
后来我还是把眼镜戴上了
And then I get the glasses, and I put them on,
坐在回家的车上
And I'm in the car on the way home,
我突然大叫起来
And suddenly I yell...
因为我从小到大
Because the big green blobs
一直注视着的大大的绿色斑点
That I had been staring at my whole life,
它们并不是绿色的斑点
They weren't big green blobs.
那是树上的绿叶
They were leaves on trees.
我看到了绿叶
I could see the leaves.
当时根本不知道  我从没见过绿叶
And I didn't even know I was missing the leaves.
甚至不知道这世上还有叶子存在
I didn't even know that leaves existed,
可突然间我能看见叶子了
And then... Leaves.
你是我的眼镜
You are glasses.
我真是个同志
I am so gay.
我是个  完全的  十足的同志
I am so, so, so gay.
我毫无疑问是个同志
I am extremely gay.
我该走了
I have to go.
男士们
Gentlemen.
我要你们认识一下
I want you to meet
西雅图圣恩医院新来的  外伤科主治医师
the new head of trauma at Seattle Grace.
欧文·亨特少校  外伤科医生
Major Owen Hunt. I'm a trauma surgeon.
德里克·谢博德  马克·斯隆
You remember Derek Shepherd,Mark Sloan.
他抢过我的病人
He stole my patient.
也抢过我的
Mine, too.
现在你们也有机会抢我的了
Now you'll get a chance to steal mine.
-十分期待  -等不及了
-Looking forward to it. -can't wait.
我刚和卫生部的一个朋友谈过
I just talked to a friend of mine at the D.O.H.
有了欧文加盟  我们在月底将被
Now that we have Owen,we are being reclassified
评定为一级外伤医院
As a level I trauma unit by the end of the month.
难怪
That explains it.
我妈妈在我5岁的时候帮我买的
So my mom bought it for me when I was 5...
对5岁的小孩来说  这礼物真够吓人的
Which is a super creepy gift for a 5 year old,
-但我还是挺喜欢的  -快跑
-But I kinda liked it. -run!
说吧  这是怎么回事
Okay. What was that all about?
刚才看见欧文了  欧文·亨特少校
I just saw Owen.Major Owen Hunt
就是那个从我胸口拔出冰锥的人
You know, the guy who pulled the icicle from my chest.
我以为他在伊拉克
Oh. I thought he was in iraq.
以前是  但现在回来了
well, yeah, he was and now he's here,
-就在我们医院里  -那又怎样
-I mean, at my hospital. -okay, so?
于是我们接吻了  其实是他吻了我
So...  So we kissed.i mean he kissed me.
这蠢透了  其实没什么  蠢得毫无意义
It was stupid. It was nothing.it was a stupid nothing.
但你觉得  他不这么认为
But you don't think he thinks it was a stupid nothing.
很显然  他喜欢我  现在又回来了
Well, I mean, he obviously likes me, and now he's back.
他回来干什么
What's he doing back?
你不会以为  他为了你退伍了吧
You don't think he quit the military for you.
那可真够粘人的  但好浪漫啊
I mean, that would be severely stalkery, but very romantic
我不会再和主治医生有瓜葛了
I'm not getting involved with another attending.
他们走了没
Coast clear?
你呼我  主任
You paged me, chief?
是的
Uh, yes, I did.
一般来讲  每次呼我上天台机坪
because generally, when I'm paged to the helipad,
肯定会有直升机降落下来
There's something landing on the helipad.yeah.
上周你成功完成了12人的多米诺手术
You pulled off a 12-person domino surgery last week.
要是每周都这样就好了
That's the kind of thing we need every week.
只有这样的经历  才能向我证明
It's also the kind of thing that shows me
你终有一天会成为一名出色的医生
That you're gonna be a great surgeon someday.
谢谢你  主任
thank you, sir
这还不够
It's not enough.
我不希望你仅仅是出色  玛兰达
I don't want you to be just great, Miranda.
我要你变成最棒的  若你想继我之后
I want you to be the best,and if you're gonna succeed me
成为这医院里最棒的普外医生的话
As the best general surgeon in this hospital,
现在就该开始了  就在今天
You need to start now, today,
这意味着你要变成我
which means you need to be me.
想通过手术来得分吗  那就行动
You want to take point on a surgery? Take point.
问题来了  应难而上  不用请示我  勇往直前
A problem comes up? Solve it.don't talk to me. Just do it.
-成为我  -成为你
-Be me.  -be you?
-成为我  -我能做到
-Be me. -I could do that.
但我不知为何你要把我呼到这天台上来
I don't know why you had to bring me all the way here to...
这就是为什么
that's why.
华盛顿湖医院送来一名10岁的女孩
Lake washington med is sending over a 10-year-old girl
得了腹部平滑肌肉瘤
With an abdominal leiomyosarcoma.
无法动手术
It's inoperable.
你立刻组建一个医疗团队
You're gonna have to put together a team
制订一个能治愈她的计划
And come up with a plan to save her.
那女孩的肿瘤无法手术  怎么救
Save a girl with an inoperable tumor?
成功非易事
It isn't easy being me.
你怎么了
What's wrong with you?
我怎么了
What's wrong with me?
我们睡在一起才一个星期
We've been sleeping together for a week,
你已经开始厌倦了
And already, you're bored.
我是个辣妹  床上工夫也了得
I'm hot and great in bed.
你到底怎么了
So what is wrong with you?
我可没说我厌倦了
Look, I didn't say I was bored.
我只是问一下是否应该
I just asked whether or not
和米雪继续在一起
I should keep sleeping with Michelle
我想知道你的看法  这难道有错吗
I'm asking if you're all-in. what's so wrong with that?
你真是野蛮人
You're a barbarian.
我怎会对十足的野蛮人投入感情
How can I be all-in with an actual barbarian?
那好吧  反正放射科的克劳迪娅
Fine. Claudia in radiology
认为我屁股超性感
I have a hot ass.
-我去找她  -你当然会的
-I'll tap that next. -you do that.
莱西  能否帮我...  莱西  我是你的室友
Oh, Lexie. Would you mind pick...Lexie, I'm your roommate.
你迟早要跟我说话的
You're eventually gonna have to talk to me.
我否定你的推断
I reject that supposition.
我驳回你的否定
I reject your rejection.
那我就忽略你对于我否定的驳回
and I ignore your rejection of my rejection.
-什么  -我不会拒绝你
-What? -I don't reject you, George.
谢谢
Thank you.
好了  就两件事
Okay, two things
早上每人都要做技能训练  这是命令
You all have a skills lab this morning. It is mandatory.
谁都别想逃脱
Don't even think about trying to get out.
第2件事  你们其中一人
Second, one of you
不用去做强制的技能训练
Will not have to go to the mandatory skills lab
因为这厮将协助我做手术
Because you will be assisting me in my efforts to remove
从一个10岁女孩身上
an inoperable tumor
摘除一个不适宜动手术的肿瘤
from a 10-year-old girl.
我来
I'll do it.
不  你不行  你有一大堆拖欠的报告没做完
No, you won't. You have a hundred delinquent charts.
做完训练好好写报告去
You will do those after the lab.
懒鬼
Slacker
既然不宜动手术  你又如何来摘除
how can you operate on an inoperable tumor?
克莱夫也出局了
Karev is also out.
我说什么了
What did I say?
你怀疑我
You doubted me.
我从不怀疑你  贝利医生
Oh, i-i-i-i don't doubt you, Dr. Bailey.
杨也出局了
Yang is out, too
为什么
Why?
你对于一个未能做完报告的住院医生
You weren't supportive of a fellow resident
落井下石  还看笑话
Who couldn't get his paperwork under control.oh!
-那是什么  格蕾  是解剖娃娃简吗  -是的
-What is that?Grey, is that anatomy jane?  -Yes.
有24个可拆卸的器官
With the 24 removable organs
以及可选的怀孕模拟部件
and the optional parts to simulate pregnancy?
是的  这样也出局吗
Yes. Does that mean I'm out, too?
-不  你跟我  -哦  这不公平
-No, that means you're in. -oh, that's not fair.
是的  下次你记得也带个丑娃娃过来
Yes! Next time, you'll know to bring in an ugly doll,
听到没  斯蒂文斯
Won't you, Stevens?
杨医生  训练室里会有什么好玩的
Dr. Yang, what exactly happens in a skills lab?
你是谁
Who are you?
我是个新实习生  赖恩 斯坦丁
I'm a new intern.rayn spalding.
我永远不会记住这名
Oh, I'm never gonna remember that.
你是  4.2号
You're, um, uh, 4.2.
3号  掩护我
Three, move.
-没事吧  -闭嘴  别动
-Is everything okay?  -Shut up. Don't move.
我是亨特医生
I'm Dr. Hunt.
在接下来的几个月里
Over the next few months,
我要教你们如何
I will be teaching you how to work
迅速而有效地去救人
Quickly and efficiently to keep someone alive
拟订的环境是  病患将在
In circumstances where the safe bet is
一小时内就死去
They're dead by the end of the hour.
有谁对活体治疗不适应吗
Now does anyone have a problem working with live tissue?
活体
Live tissue?
有的话就说出来  或者直接离开
anyone? Speak now.in fact, leave now.
否则  你们今天一天都听我的
If not, I own you for the rest of the day.
好  开始吧
Good. Here we go.
每个住院医生一头猪  实习生辅助  看着
Each resident gets a pig. interns assist. Hang on.
开始吧
Go ahead.
救活它们
Save their lives.
你真是个恶魔
You're a monster.
它们麻醉了  感觉不到痛
They're under. They didn't feel any pain.
你可以问问兽医
Ask the veterinarian.
-你刺伤了它们  -那就让我们来拯救它们
-You stabbed them. -so we can save them.
我们可以用人体模型做练习
We can practice on--on surgical mannequins.
同样能达到学习的效果
We can learn to do the exact same stuff.
你是想不干了吗
does that mean you're out?
是的  我不干了
Yeah, I'm out.
这样的话  谁要两头猪
In that case, who wants two pigs?
托瑞 巴切拉  10岁
Tori begler, age 10.
托瑞有腹部平滑肌肉瘤
Tori has an abdominal leiomyosarcoma.
肿瘤包围在她腹动脉
The tumor is wrapped around her celiac artery,
脾动脉  和她的左胃动脉附近
Her splenic arteraynd her left gastric artery.
这类肿瘤很难摘除
It is considered unresectable.
你听懂她说什么了吗
Did you understand a word of that, Tori?
没有
Not really.
格蕾
Grey.
这是解剖娃娃简
This is anatomy jane.
她看上去真好玩
She's kinda funny looking.
的确很好看
She is funny looking,
但她很有用的
But she's very helpful.
我们的肿瘤呢
So the tumor...
就在你腹部的下方
Is way down here in your belly.
因为在这些器官下方  所以很难摘除
It's hard to get at because it's underneath all these organs
很难  但并非不可能  是吗
Hard, but not impossible, right?
我们会尽一切努力
We're gonna try everything we can.
你们的努力  应当包括胸外科的主治医师
Everything you can should include your cardiothoracic gal.
西雅图伯斯医院的斯图医生
Dr. Stewart at Seattle pres
他说血管系统是一个大问题
Said the vasculature is the big problem,
你们医院挖走了他们最好的
And you stole the best cardiovascular surgeon
最好的心脏外科医生
He's ever had.
如果她不参与托瑞的手术  我们立刻就走
If she's not on Tori's team,we're leaving
去旧金山
And going to san francisco.
软糖要吗  自己做的
Fudge? It's homemade.
我爱死这家医院了
I love this hospital.
别废话了  快来
Yeah, enough small talk.come on.
-想上课?  -不授课  只做爱
-More lessons?  -No, no lessons. Just sex.
不要幻想  要直接的传统的
Nothing fancy.just plain old missionary,
男女之间的做爱
Boy/girl, penis/vagina sex.
我认真的  不许淫言秽语
Oh.hey, hey, I mean it.no dirty talk.
不提爱瑞  不准讲话  专心做爱
No Erica talk. No talk.just grunting and grinding.
-现在谁在讲下流话?  -闭嘴
- Now who's talking dirty? - Shut up.
-为什么要这么做  -我在检验一个理论
-What's this about?  -I'm testing a theory.
很好  看起来不错
Good. That looks good.
你在抚慰这头猪吗
Are you petting the pig?
-我只是在  -别抚慰猪
-I-i was  -stop petting the pig.
看起来你花了很多时间做缝合
You seem to be spending a lot of time on that anastamosis.
你叫什么来着
What was your name again?
杨  克里斯蒂娜·杨
Yang. Cristina Yang.
没错  过来看看他的猪
Right. Come take a look at this guy's pig.
-欧麦利的猪?  -好戏要上演了
-O'malley?  -Oh, this is gonna be good.
这里  给杨医生让个地方
Here, make way for Dr. Yang.
看到了吗  他已经止住血了
You see what he did?He stopped the bleeding,
他已经开始处理肝脏的破损了
And then he moved onto his liver lacerations.
是的  不过草率的缝合可能引起并发症
yes, but sloppy work can lead to complications.
两天后这只猪将开始吐血
Two days from now when this pig starts vomiting blood,
欧麦利到时候会后悔现在没有做周全
O'malley's gonna wish he'd been a little more thorough.
他可以等到猪的病情稳定下来
He can come back later and make things pretty
再回头把伤口整理好
When his pig is stable.
同时  你的猪已经酸中毒体温下降
Meanwhile, your pig is getting acidotic and hypothermic.
如果不是猪  而是某个瘦弱的小孩
If this was some scrawny kid instead of a pig,
他已经死了  速度至上  克莉丝汀
He'd be dead by now.quick and dirty, cristine.
娜  克里斯蒂娜
"A." Cristina.
好  现在把导管插入腹腔动脉
Okay, let's guide the catheter into the celiac axis.
注入氟代
Turning on the fluoro.
那是什么  等我一下
What the...uh, excuse me a second.
你们不能待在这里
Uh, hello.you can't be in here.
那是帕特叔叔和简阿姨
That's my uncle Pat and aunt Jean.
他们是怕我觉得孤独
They like to make sure I don't get lonely.
她不孤独  格蕾医生和我会照顾好她
She's not lonely. Dr. Grey and I are very entertaining.
好吧  就这样吧
Uh, uh, okay, fine.
虽然他们可以待在那里
Um, they have to stayin there, though.
这里有辐射
There's radiation in here.
好的  注射染色剂
All right, let's, uh,inject dye.
一切还好吗
Is everything okay?
没事
Uh, it--it's fine.
欧文·亨特是一个凶手  一个虐待狂
Owen Hunt is a murdering,sadistic bastard.
我猜猜看  是实验室培训?
Let me guess.first wet lab?
他拿刀刺猪  毫无反抗的猪
He's stabbing pigs,defenseless pigs.
或者应该用他的话讲  是活体
Or as he likes to call them,"Live tissue,"
可上帝说你应该叫它们动物
Because god forbid you should call them animals.
他是创伤科的新头头  斯蒂文斯
Well, he is the new headof trauma, Stevens.
也许不合你意  但是这是他做事的方式
It may not be ideal, but if that's how he does things,
-你应该学着去适应  -我们不需要用活物
-You should roll with it.  -we don't need live subjects.
守则第一条不是说不要伤害吗
What happened tofirst do no harm?
这不仅仅指不要伤人  也包括所有生物
That's not just about humans.that's about all living things.
事实上  我觉得仅仅是指不要伤人
Actually, I thinkit's just about humans.
我以室友的身份
I'm saying this to you as my roommate
而不是你手下的身份告诉你
and not my attending
你恶心死我了
You disgust me.
该死
Damn it.
怎么了  你感觉不好吗
What,it wasn't good for you?
不可能
Impossible.
不是感觉不好  而是因为感觉太好了
It's not that it wasn't good. It's that it was.
说句谢谢就可以了
A "Thank you"Would've been nice.
是你呼我吗
You paged me?
有个10岁的小女孩
I've got a 10-year-old girl
她的主动脉附近有颗肿瘤
With a tumor wrapped around her aorta.
我在组织医疗小组
I'm putting together a team.
她的血管造影的结果?
This is her angio?
-她只是  -肿瘤包围了五条主动脉
-She just  -this thing is wrapped around five major arteries.
很糟糕  但是我已经有主意了
It's bad, but I've gota couple of ideas
恭喜你
Good for you.
可以那活人做试验
Try them on someone who might actually live.
我承认  看起来非常糟糕
I-i admit,it doesn't look great,
但是她的家人提到了你  所以我想
But her family mentioned you by name, so I thought
很好  但我不在乎
that's nice,but I really don't care.
但是我在乎
Well, I do.
别感情用事  贝利
Don't get emotional, Bailey.
没人喜欢感情用事的女生
No one likes a girl who gets emotional.
虽然如此  我坚持要求你加入我的小组
Still... I'd like you on my team.
太抱歉了  小家伙
I'm sorry about this,little guy.
你肯定很难过
It must have been awful.
你本该在漂亮的乡村农场里
One day, you're at some beautiful farm out in the country
呼吸着新鲜的空气  懒懒地躺在泥巴上
Breathing in the fresh air,lounging in the mud
和你的朋友在一起  可现在
With all your friends,and next thing you know,
你却被抓紧实验室  注射镇定剂  还被刺伤
You're sedated and stabbed in some skills lab.
缝合好它  3号
Get it together,three.
大家注意
Heads-up, everyone.
你  带着你的实习生去急诊室
You, take your interns down to the e.r.
-我马上下去找你们  -外伤?
-I'll meet you down there. -Trauma?
来了六个病人  实验结束  做你的记录
Multiple m.v.c Six incoming.you, lab's over. Do your charts.
我的猪怎么办
What about my pig?
-她来接手  -什么
-She's got it.  -what?
你留下来
You're staying here
等下  来了六个外伤病人  我却要留下
Wait,with a half-dozen crash victims coming into the pit?
这也有四个病患  救活它们
You got four struggling victims right here. Keep them alive
等下  所有的？
Wait, all of them?
克莱夫可以去医治受伤的人
Karev gets to work on mangled people,
-我就和这300多磅的猪肉待在一起?
-And I'm stuckwith 300 pounds of bacon?
活猪肉
Live bacon,
我回来的时候它们最好还是活的
And it better be that way when I get back.
35岁的后座乘客
35-year-old backseat passenger.
额头撞上了玻璃
Forehead versus window,and the window won.
同时左边有二级烧伤
Also has second-degree burns on the left side.
-途中体征稳定  -去1号外伤室  什么情况
Vitals stable en route.trauma one. What do you got?
切拉斯 惠特  46岁  腹部持续瘀斑
Charles Hiott, 46, positive ecchymosis over abdomen.
途中最后测得血压是96和68
Last b.p. In the field--96 or 68.
-会用超声波探外伤吗  -会
-Do you know how to use a trauma ultrasound?  -Yes.
那好  这个病人交给你了  去2号外伤室
In that case, he's all yours in trauma two.
-怎么  什么事  -克莱夫医生传呼我们
What do you-can I help you gentlemen? -Dr. Karev paged us.
他不应这么做  我们可以应付的  谢谢
Well, he shouldn't have.we got it covered. Thanks.
这个病人头部受伤还伴有烧伤
you have a head injury and burns
我觉得你们应付不了
So I don't thinkyou have it covered.
克莱夫  你是医生吗
Karev, are you a doctor?
-当然  -你有能力评定一个病人的病情吗
-Uh, yes, sir.  -Are you capable of assessing a patient's injuries?
-当然  -如我所言  我们可以应付
-Yep.  -Like I said,we got it covered.
我们已经来了
You know what? We're here.
为什么不让我们帮忙
Why don't you let us just dive in?
谢谢你的心意  谢博德
Appreciate the offer, Shepherd,
不过我想让我的医生学会怎么治疗外伤
But I want my residents to learn how to deal with trauma.
如果只站在一旁看主治医生工作
They're not gonna learn as muchor as fast if they stand back
根本没办法学会  除非主治医生是我
And watch attendings do it,unless that attending is me.
3家医院都拒绝做这个手术
Three other hospitals have already sent them away,
我们够聪明的话  我们也应该拒绝
And if we were smart,we would do the same thing.
你是怎么了
What is the matter with you?
我们可以试着沿着胃部切除
We can try and cut around the stomach.
不  唯一的方法就是把胃取出来
No, the only way to do that is to actually take it out.
有人做过活体自体移植
They've done ex vivo autotransplants.
是的  但得把肝和肾一起取出
Yeah, with livers and kidneys.
如果我们把胃和肾都取出来呢
So why don't we take out the stomach and the kidneys?
如果想让她死  这样再好不过了
Oh, yeah, that'd be great if you wanted to kill her.
我们在讨论
We're talking about
完全不同的两路供血
Two completely different blood supplies here.
所以  这主意不好  格蕾
So, no, not a good idea, Grey.
他们是谁
Who are those people?
是托瑞的爸爸蓝迪
Uh, that's Tori's dad Randy
叔叔帕特以及妻子简
And his brother Pat and Pat's wife Jean
哥哥大卫
And Tori's brother David and--
他们为什么盯着我们看  贝利医生
Why are they staring at us,Dr. Bailey?
我认为他们不是在盯着我们看  主任
I don't think they're staringat us, chief.
他们只是在等待  看看我们有什么消息
I think they're just waiting,seeing if we have any news.
听好  在我回来时你们最好想出办法
Look, try and come up with something before I get back.
拉下百叶窗  格蕾
Close the blinds, Grey.
你呼我
You paged me?
兰博已经失控了(第一滴血男主角)
Rambo is completely out of control.
什么
Excuse me?
亨特  他把我踢出了急诊室
Hunt. He kicked me out of my own e.r.
他把病人治死了?
Did he kill somebody?
-还没  -等弄死再呼我
-Not yet.  -Then call me when he does.
-理查德  -我没空  有个10岁的女孩快死了
-Richard.  -i don't have time for it, shep.i have a dying 10 year old
医疗小组正在激烈争论治疗方案
And a team of doctors who can't stop bickering long enough
除了你的女朋友
To solve a problem,except for your girlfriend,
她一直在玩玩具
who's more interested in playing with a doll.
解剖娃娃简
anatomy jane?
她一直带着这个玩具在医院晃悠
She dragged that thing all around the hospital
那时候她才5岁
When she was 5 years old,
现在还玩娃娃  一点都不可爱
And let me tell you,it was cuter in a child.yeah.
-有主意了吗  -你觉得怎么样
-Any luck?  -What do you think?
我知道你想成为第一  理查德
Look, I know you want to be number one, Richard,
但我们不能每一个慈善案例都接手
But we can't take in every charity case that comes along.oh.
这是在浪费医疗资源
It is a huge waste of resources.
你来决定  贝利医生
It's your call,Dr. Bailey.
格蕾  把玩具收起来  现在不是玩乐时间
Grey, put that away.this isn't playtime.
我不是玩  我在思考
I'm not playing.I'm thinking.
如果我们只拿出被肿瘤妨碍血液供给
What if we just took out each of the organs
的那部分器官怎么样
Where the tumor interferes with the blood supply?
同时夹住主动脉
By the time you clamp off the aorta,
你在拿其他器官冒险
You run the risk of damaging the other organs.
如果一个接一个取出呢
Even if you take them out one by one?
没那么多时间的  格蕾
You don't have the time,Grey.
如果我们制造时间呢
What about if we made the time?
贝利医生  可以把手术预告板添上了
Dr. Bailey, let's throw some stuff up on the board.
CT显示是硬脑膜下血肿
C.t. Showed a subdural hematoma.
-我应该预定手术室吗  -事有轻重缓急
-Should I book an o.r.?  -First things first.
他的头皮血流的很凶
His scalpis bleeding like stink.
-你该怎么做  -通常我会找谢博德
-What do you do next?  -Normally, I'd page Shepherd.
谢博德不在  你该怎么止血
Shepherd's not here. What do you do to stop the bleeding?
-缝合伤口  然后包扎  -那要花两个小时
-Suture the laceration,tie off the bleeders.-that'll take two hours.
看看四周你能用什么器材来止血呢
What would you use in this room to take care of this?
订书钉
Uh... Staples?
伤口在额头  你  你想让他
It's his forehead.you... You want this guy
-后半辈子变成怪物吗?  -皮胶
To look like frankenstein for the rest of his life?-Skin glue.
非常好  克莱夫  清理伤口  缝合吧
Excellent, Karev.clean it, close it,
然后加压包扎
And stick a pressure dressing over it.
-你感觉如何  惠特先生  -不太好
-How are you feeling,mister, uh, Hiott?  -Not too good.
你决定怎么治疗呢
How are we gonna make Mr. Hiott feel better?
超声波发现了体液外流
The ultrasound showed free fluid.
我要带他去做CT确认一下
We'll get him to a c.t. To confirm,
他应该需要手术
But he's pretty much o.r. Bound.
非常好  那是破伤风针吗
Excellent. Is that tetanus?
你知道破伤风针的发明归功于谁吗
You know who you have to thank for the invention
斯蒂文斯
Of the tetanus shot, Stevens?
马  最初的实验对象就是马
Horses. The first experiments--done on horses.
你们将要取出她所有的腹部器官
You want to take outall of her abdominal organs--
-肠  胃  所有的  -一次全取出来
-Intestine, stomach,everything?  -All at once?
没错
That's right.
我们会把器官放在冰上同时切除肿瘤
We'll put the orga on ice while we dissect out the tumor,
然后用人造移植来接通血管
Then reconnect the vessels using synthetic grafts
-放回器官  -为什么华盛顿的
-And put the organs back in.  -why didn't Graham
格尔曼和费歇尔没有提出这个方案
Or Fleisher over at lake washington suggest this?
他们的医术也很精湛呀
They'rea couple of smarties.
很可能因为这样的手术从来没有过
Probably becauseit's never been done before.
风险非常大
It is extremely risky.
每一步都有可能出差错
There are any number of things that could go wrong.
我不知道  蓝迪  也许我们该继续化疗
I-I don't know, Randy.maybe we should try more chemo.
冒昧的说  begler夫人
Uh, with all due respect,Mrs. Begler,
我认为托瑞已经没有时间化疗
I don't think there's time for that.
这个手术能救活她吗
Is it gonna save her life?
这是你们最好的机会
It's your best shot...
唯一的机会
Your only shot.
那就做吧
Then do it.
好的
Okay.
贝利医生 我不是兽医
Dr. Bailey...um, I'm not a vet.
我也很珍惜在活体上
And while I can appreciate the value
磨练技艺的机会
Of practicing technique on live tissue,
可急诊室来了那么多病人
There's a multiple m.v.c.in the pit,
如果能够在人体上授课
And my education would be far better served
我将受益更多
Practicing on humans.
-现在谁在看护那些猪  -我的实习生
-Well, w--who's babysitting the pigs right now?  -My interns.
亨特医生是要你还是实习生去照顾猪的
Did major Hunt order the internsto babysit the pigs or you?
-这不是重点  -那就找到重点  我没空理会
-That's not the point.-well, make it the point.i don't have time for this.
我要从一个人身上取6个器官
I'm about to take six organsout of a person.
看  这不公平  我不是懒人医生
Well, see? That--that--that's not fair.I'm not Dr. Do little.
其他动物们
The zebras and the elephants
会为此庆幸有个好医生的
are thanking their lucky stars for that.
我有问题
I have a question.
既然涉及到左肾动脉
Why aren't we taking out the kidney
为什么我们不取出肾
Since the left renal arteryis involved?
因为不这么做我们也可以清除肿瘤
Because we can remove the tumorwithout doing that,
何必多此一举
So why bother?
-我还有一个问题  -说吧
-I have another question.  -yes?
为什么你不能直视我
Why can't you look at me?
什么
What?
你不肯看着我
You can't look at me.
你今天一整天都没有正眼看过我
You haven't been able to look at me all day.
我觉得这是你的错觉
I think you're imagining things.
我可不这么觉得
Oh. I don't think I am.
但是  如果你这么说
But, hey, if you say so.
没错  我是这么说
I do. I say so.
与其去想什么
So instead of worrying
我到底有没有看着你
About whether or not I'm looking at you,
不如集中精神来救治这个小女孩
Maybe you should concentrateon saving the 10-year-old girl
我们正要把她的内脏全取出来
That we're about to eviscerate.
格蕾医生  我们为什么要查看腹腔底部
Dr. Grey, why do we dose that down in quadrants?
这样可以让我们看清楚血管
Uh, so we can geta good luck at the vessels
-以确保有足够的用来重建  -非常好
To make sure we have enough for reconstruction.  -Very good.
请在这里吸一下
A little suction right in here, please.
巴切拉先生打电话找你
Mr. Begler is on the phone.
-接待室问能否把电话接进来  -不行
O.r. Desk wants to know if they can put him through. No.
-他坚持让你接  -我真的很忙
He's pretty insistent.and I'm pretty busy.
你能把这个举高一点吗  格蕾医生
If you could hold this up a little bit higher, Dr. Grey.
我想确保避免
I want to make sure to avoid--
这个
That.
-好吧  快拿止血钳来  -麻烦再拿一个
Okay, let's get some clamps.another clamp, please.
-这里  -再挂一袋血
Right there.let's hang another bag of blood.
你最好期望她的主动脉不那么脆弱
You better hope the aorta is not that friable,
否则全世界的血都用上也救不了这姑娘
Otherwise, all the blood inthe world won't save this girl.
赖恩  莱姬的脉搏是多少
Ryan, what's reggie's pulse?
真的吗  维尔布的心率有102
Really? because wilbur's at 102,
这可不太妙
and I'm pretty sure that's bad.
波波像头牛  她的心率只有52
Babe's like an ox.hers is 52.
别乱起名字
Hey, no cute names.
他们可不是宠物
They're not pets.
他们是实验对象
They're subjects.
我们要做的不是对它们深情款款
It's not our job to get all affectionate.
而是保证他们活命
It's our job to keep them alive...
那样才能让某些认为我们无能的人
So the attending who somehow thinks we're incapable
对我们无话可说
Can choke on his words at the end of the day.
所以我不想听你们叫它们维尔布或是波波
So I don't want to hear wilbur or babe.
要是你们想称呼它们
You want to call them something,
就叫它们香肠或者熏火腿吧
Call them sausage or prosciutto.
维尔布脉搏过速了
Wilbur's crashing.
什么  你做了什么
What? What did you do?
-我什么也没  -我要重新开胸
I don't--i don't--i gotta reopen that thoracotomy.
把胸盘拿过来
Uh, pull that chest tray back over here.yeah.
-贝利医生  -我数到3  一起移动器官
Dr. Bailey.removing the organs on three.
准备好了
Ready
1  2  3
one, two, three
很好  就这样  给我吧
Very good.all right. Let me have it.
我要中号和大号的血管环
I'll need medium and large vessel loops
-好切除肿瘤  -巴切拉又来电话了
To dissect out the tumor.Mr. Begler again.
他想跟你谈谈她女儿的事
He wants to talk to you about his daughter.
我现在很忙
Well, I'm pretty busy right now.
我已经告诉过他了
I already told him that.
-那再告诉他一遍  -我跟他说了18遍了
Well, tell him again.I've told him 18 times.
老大  你得去跟他们谈谈
Chief, you need to go talk to them.
嘿  是你让我管事的
Hey, you did put me in charge.
我去去就来
I'll be back.
怎么回事
What t hell?
看看这里
Look at this crap.
那是胶水吗  你用了皮胶吗
Is that glue?You used skin glue?
亨特医生想让他尽快离开
Dr. Hunt wanted to get him outta there pretty quick.
对  没错  亨特医生没让你
Yeah, well, because Dr. Hunt didn't have you
修复好伤口  这会毁了病人半张脸
Revise the wound,he could lose half his face.
没有金刚钻  别揽瓷器活  叫行的人过来
You can't rotate a flap,you call someone who can.
他说急诊室就像战场
Well, he says the e.r. is like being in the field.
只能利用能到手的资源
You use what's available
我们这儿哪里像战场了  克莱夫
what, uh, qualifies us as a war zone, Karev,
是人手不够的礼品店
Our undermanned gift shop,
还是咖啡车里的温饮料
The lukewarm drinksfrom the coffee cart?
他是个蠢蛋  你还想怎样
He's a meatballer.what do you expect?
蠢蛋吗  外科小伙子们
Meatballer?Trauma guys.
他们就这样把它胶在一起了
they just slap it together.
韦伯医生  托瑞怎么样了
Dr. Webber, how's tori?
她情况稳定  我们正在切除肿瘤
She's stable. We're removing the tumor right now.
实际上  我应该在那儿帮忙的
Actually, I should bein there to help,
可我被你叫出来了
But I'm out here instead
我只是需要知道最新消息
I just needed an update.
告诉你最新消息并不重要  先生
It's not important that you get an update right now, sir.
重要的是我们医院最好的医生
What's important is the best doctors
现在要全力以赴的医治你女儿
We have in this hospital are focused on your daughter.
打电话会让我们分神
Calls don't help us focus.
打断我们是会影响我们的
Interruptions don't help us focus
抱歉  我知道有时我们拖了后腿
I'm sorry. I know we have been underfoot sometimes.
可我们去过很多医院了
But we have been to a lot of hospitals.
医院可不是容易获得信息的地方
And hospitals are not easy places to get information.
实际上  很多时候
In fact, a lot of times,it's impossible to even get
都很难和医生说上话
A doctor to talk to u
或者是让医生们互相交流
Or to get the doctorsto talk to each other.
我不知道这是怠慢
And I don't know if it's neglect
还是自负作怪  我也不关心
Or their egos getting inthe way, and I don't care.
可我们只是想照顾好我们的女儿
We're just trying to take care of our little girl.
她才10岁  又病又怕
She's 10, she's scaredand she's sick.
我们只是想尽全力照顾好她
We're doing whatever we can.
请继续像这样好好照顾她
Don't ever stop taking care of her like that.
斯蒂文斯  你用过切割缝合器吗
Stevens, have you ever used a g.i.a. Stapler?
没有  但我准备好了  我能搞定
No, but I'm ready.i can handle it.
回答我三个问题  我就让你来
Answer me three questions,and I'll let you
好的
Okay.
问题一  小儿麻痹症疫苗的发明
Question one--polio vaccine.
是因为哪种动物做出的牺牲
Which animal do you have to thank for that?
这有必要吗
Is this really necessary?
要是你想用那缝合器的话
Only if you want to use that stapler.
鳍肢婴儿
Flipper babies.
-什么  -鳍肢婴儿
-What?-Flipper babies.
1950年代有1万多有缺陷的婴儿出生
10,000 babies were born with birth defects in the 1950s
由于他们母亲怀孕期间服用安眠药所致
Because their pregnant mothers took thalidomide,
首先应用在豚鼠上
First developedon guinea pigs.
-而在豚鼠身上没有副作用  -你想说什么
-The guinea pigs didn't have any side effects.  -Your point?
我想说的是动物和人类
My pointis that humans and animals
生理结构不同  对药物的反应也不同
Have different physiologies,they have different reactions.
他们可能对药物的反应不同
They can have different reactions.
并不意味着一定会不同
Doesn't mean that they will.
对那1万名婴儿和他们母亲说吧
Tell that to those 10,000 babiesand their mothers.
其实小儿麻痹症疫苗  是用老鼠和猴子做实验做的
So the polio vaccine--developed using mice and monkeys.
你自己留着切割缝合器吧  那不值得
You can keep your stapler.it's not worth it.
告诉我莱姬和帕迪的情况
Give me the status on reggie and paddy.
莱姬很好  帕迪脉搏迟缓但稳定
reggie's fine. Paddy'spulse ox is low but stable.
-波波呢  -一直很稳定
And babe?Holding steady.
我以为我们不该给它们起名字
I thought we weren't supposed to give them names.
我可以给他们编号  可要是我告诉你
I could give them numbers,but then I'd probably tell you
三号需要抗生素
Three needs antibiotics
我怕你会把针扎到格蕾的屁股上
And find you shoving a needle in Grey's ass.
它的生命体征越来越弱了
His vitals are getting worse.damn it
你检查它的肺了吗
uh, did you check his lung again?
我把一整片肺叶都拿掉了
I already took out an entire lobe.
下行主动脉呢
what abou this descending aorta?
你知道吗  莱西
You know what?Just can it,Lexopedia
我什么都试过了
I've tried everything.
没脉搏了 我们需要扩大切口
Pulseless. Uh, that's it.we need to get more exposure.
你还要把它切大
you're opening him up more?
所有人都来帮忙
I need everyone's help.stem to stern.
要是它承受不了怎么办  你会杀了它的
What--what if he can't take it?You could--you could kill him.
不要感情用事
Don't get emotional.
准备好给它按摩心脏  给我手术刀
Just get ready to start massaging his heart. Scalpel.
贝利医生  你能再向下切一点吗
Dr. Bailey,can you dissect down anymore?
没有什么好切的了  几乎没剩下什么动脉
There's nothing to dissect.there's barely any artery left.
要是我们延伸人造血管呢
What about if we extend the gore-tex graft?
不行  剩下的组织已经很脆弱了
No, what's left is too friable.
那我们不能把器官和血管重新连接了吗
So we can't reconnect the organs to the vessels?
现在不时候
Not at this moment no
可要是我们不能把器官和血管重新连接
But if we can't reconnect the organs,
血液不能重新灌注  它们会衰竭的
They won't reperfuse and they'll just die
是的
Yes, they will.
现在谈器官移植是不是太晚了
Is it too late for a transplant?
那我们得找到六个健康器官
Well, we'd have to find six good organs
在8小时之内
In about eight hours.
现在谈器官移植太晚了
it's too late for a transplant.
给格蕾颁块金牌
And a gold star for Grey.
我们可以试着用更多的人造血管
We could try to put in more gore-tex.
给她用更多的合成材料吗
Oh, put even more synthetic material in her?
嫁接在隐静脉怎么样
What about a saphenous vein graft?
不行 她已经开始酸中毒了
No, she's already getting acidotic.
这种事情得预先计划
That sort of thing has to be preplanned
对  那你的意见是
yeah, so what's your idea?
不好意思
Excuse me?
我是说你这么爱毙掉我们的意见
I mean, you're good at shooting down every idea we come up with
那你的意见是什么
What's yours?
我的意见是不该做这手术  贝利医生
It was my idea not to do this in the first place, Dr. Bailey.
-对  你一有机会就会这么说  -闭嘴
Yeah, you made that very clear every chance you got.  -Shut up.
我不在乎谁什么时候  出了什么主意
I don't care who had what idea when.
管好你们自己
Get over yourselves.
别吵了  互相交流交流
Shut up and talk to each other.
用人的脐静脉血管  怎么样
What about...Using...human umbilical vein?
条件具备  肝素化也完成了
I mean, ready to go,already heparinized.
好  这主意我喜欢  爱瑞  你怎么看
Okay. I like it.Erica, what do you think?
应该能行
It could work.
这归贝利医生决定  如果她想这么做
It's Dr. Bailey's call.if she wants to do it...
我想
I do.
这样的话  我们开工吧
In that case, let's do it.
瓣膜处理的不错
Nice work on the valve.
起初猪身上实验的  但最近更多用的是奶牛
First developed in pigs,but more recently cows. Moo.
今天你打击够我了吗
Are you done beating me up for the day?
因为我要回家了
Because I'd like to go home.
-我只是想试着教你们  -你想教我们
I was just trying to teach you.  -You want to teach us?
带我们去模拟实验室  用塑料人模型
Take us to the simulab with the plastic guys
他们有心跳和血压
Who have heart rates and blood pressure
你割到动脉时还会发牢骚
And croak when you nick an artery.
不用手术刀割开真的皮肤  斯蒂文斯
until you apply scalpel to skin, Stevens,
你学不到任何东西的
You're just going through the motions.
这种做法已经过时了
that attitude,that's from before.
我们现在有先进科技
We have the technology now.
我们不用去折磨活生生的动物
We don't have to torture live creatures.
你不要指责我折磨动物
no, you don't get to accuse me of torture.
那些动物感觉不到疼痛
Those animals felt no pain.
你怎么知道  你怎么可能知道
you don't know that.you don't know that.
你根本不知道它们的感觉
You don't know what they felt.
你不知道它们有多害怕
You don't know how scared they were.
动物都是敏感而聪明的生物
Animals are sensitiveand intelligent creatures.
不是我感情用事
And that is not me being emotional,
这是个简单的事实
That is simply the truth.
你想让我学习你的方法
You want me to learn from your methods?
你想让我在你身上学到东西
You want me to learn anything from you?
那就别在我面前  刺伤猪猡
Then don't stab pigs in front of me
然后还告诉我天不是蓝的
And tell me that the sky isn't blue.
你在折磨上帝创造的生物
You are torturing god's creatures
在这个时代我们已经有了现代科技
In an age where we have the technology
不用再那么做了
That no longer requires us to.
要是你想这么做  随便你
If you want to do that,go ahead,
但别告诉我  我没有资格当医生
But don't tell me I'm less of a doctor for walking away.
加油  维尔布  别这样
Come on, wilbur,don't do this.
他的心脏不再充血了
His heart's not filling.
用双手给它做按摩
No, uh, massage it with both hands,
像个猪心三明治一样
Like a--like a heart sandwich.
好的  很好
Okay.good, good.
就在这儿  我真傻  看这儿
There. Right there.stupid. Look at that.
那刀通过横膈膜直穿他的脾脏
The knife went through his diaphragm right into his spleen.
好的  给我止血钳
Okay, um,hand me those clamps.
腹部左下象限有积血
We've got some blood pooling the lower left quadrant.
有谁看见血从哪流出来的吗
Can anybody see where it's coming from?
是这条血管
Here. This graft.
给我血管钳和4个0型可吸收线
Satinsky clampsand 4-0 prolene.
剪刀
Scissors.
我们在等你  贝利医生
We're waiting,Dr. Bailey.
好了  马上就出来了
Okay, this thing'scoming out.
我们还在等  贝利医生
Still waiting, Dr. Bailey.
好的  吸一下  清理干净
Okay.suction. Clear it out.
好的  拿掉止血钳
Okay, release clamps.
坚持  坚持  就在这儿
Hold on, hold on, hold on.right in here.
还是没用
Still nothing.
没有脉搏
No pulsation.
加油
Come on. Come on.
再灌注完成
Reperfusion complete.
自发心跳恢复
Heart's beating on its own.
太好了
All right.
大伙做的不错
Everyone, hell of a job.
我知道女人会不高兴
I've known women to be upset
是因为她们不能达到高潮
Because they couldn't make it to the big finish.
从来都与我无关
Never had anything to do with me.
通常是她们自己的原因
Usually something to dowith their anatomy.
我从没见过一个女人
The point is, I've never known a woman to be upset
因为能达到高潮而不高兴
Because she could take a curtain call.
我搞不懂你  托瑞斯
You're a conundrum, Torres.
爱瑞  今早哭了
Erica cried this morning...
在床上  我们做完爱之后
In bed... After sex.
这是对你的赞美
That was a compliment...for you.
哭声就是一种赞美
The crying was a compliment.
不是对我的赞美  她只是
It wasn't a compliment for me.she was--it was--
在倾吐心声  她...
She was having a revelation.she was having...
和爱瑞做爱的感觉很棒
The sex is awesome with Erica.
我们都到了高潮  这很
We've reached awesome,which is...
很棒
Awesome.
是的  可和你做爱也很棒
Yes, but it's also awesome with you.
那是怎么回事
So what's the problem?
我为什么没觉察出区别
I guess I thought there should be a difference...
你和爱瑞之间
between you and Erica.
如果我
I mean, if I'm...
你们之间应该有区别的
There should be a difference.
我和爱瑞的区别是
The difference between me and Erica...
我知道你昨晚跟她做过爱
is that I know you had sex with her 12 hours ago.
她却不知道你跟我也做爱
She doesn't know you had sex with me,
你认为自己对她不忠
And that makes you a cheater.
你想有外遇吗  我没问题
Do you want to be a cheater? Because I'm fine with it.
问题在于  你行吗
The question is, are you?
我要去把那少将给训一顿
I'm gonna yell at the major general.
-你来不来  -当然  马上去
- You want to come? - Hell yeah. Be right there.
你好  托瑞斯
Hey, Torres.
你好
Hey.
-亨特  能跟你说句话吗  -行啊
- Hunt, can I talk to you?  - Sure.
克莱夫
Karev.
不  你留下
No, no, he can stay.
你想让克莱夫听到你是怎么毁了
You want Karev to hear how you screwed up the flap
那个病人的头皮  我没意见
on my head trauma,that's fine with me.
我只负责保住他的命  我做到了
My job's to keep him alive. That's what I did.
不  你差点让那个人
No, what you did was almost maim a guy
下半生都残废了
for the rest of his life.
你该庆幸没有造成出血
You're lucky I saved the blood supply.
要是你们会怎么做
So what would you have done?
你有个头皮严重受伤的病人
Well, you got a man with a deep scalp wound
两个全国顶尖的医生
and two of the best surgeons in the country
站在一旁愿意帮你
standing 10 feet away from him.
我若是你  我就会请他们帮忙
I would've asked those two surgeons to step in.
我若是你我就会这么做
That's what I would've done.
我是问从医学的角度
I mean medically.
你们有更好的办法来救治他吗
What would you have done medically so I can do better?
听着  我们做事的方法不同
Listen, I recognize there's different ways of doing things,
根本上的不同
Even the basics.
在医院里  你们会去救一个快死了的人
Over here, if someone appears dead, you go to them first.
在伊拉克  如果一个人快死了  没人会去救
In Iraq, if someone appears dead, you don't go to them.
这就是我的做事方法  如果你们
This is day one for me, so if you think
有更好的办法就说出来  我会听的
there's a better way,then tell me, and I'll listen.
你们俩
Again, both of you,
干得很好
great job.
谢谢
Thank you.
你有什么问题吗  贝利医生
Is there a problem, Dr. Bailey?
我只是不敢相信
I just find it hard to believe
你居然会接受主任的祝贺
You're accepting congratulations,
你打从一开始就不想做这个手术
Considering you didn't want to do this operation in the first place.
好不容易把你请进行手术室
And when you finally did do it,
你又处处跟我作对
You fought me every step of the way.
但我这个顶尖的心脏外科医生
And yet, you still had a world-class heart surgeon
帮你完成了手术
by your side.
你也许是个不错的外科医生
You may be a fine surgeon--
这我知道
God knows I know that--
但今天不是
But not today.
今天你是个讨厌鬼
Today you were a pain in the ass--
唱反调  自大  从头到底让人讨厌
A nay-saying, bullying, consistently negative pain in the ass.
你都不愿意给我一点点鼓励
At no point did you encourage me or do anything
好让我对手术至少有那么一点自信
to make me think this surgery could be anything but a failure.
不止是我一个这么觉得
And it wasn't just me.
你给我们所有人造成了巨大的压力
You made it as hard as humanly possible for all of us.
我们今天的确干得很出色
So, yeah, we did do a nice job today.
很出色  但不是因为你
We did a great job today,but that wasn't thanks to you.
而是因为我  和主任
That was thanks to me and the chief
以及梅瑞狄斯·格蕾
and Meredith Grey
以及解剖娃娃简
and anatomy Jane.
波波很强壮
Babe is indestructible.
我切除了一部分肝脏和小肠
She lost a part of her liver and small bowel,
但它现在很稳定
but she's been doing fine.
我们给维尔布做了主动脉阻断和心脏按摩
We had to cross-clamp Wilbur's aorta and massage his heart.
我起初找不到出血点
I couldn't locate the source of his bleeding
但后来我发现它的隔膜上有个洞
until I found a hole in his diaphragm
才知道是脾脏破损
and realized he had a splenic laceration.
它就像个斗士  正在康复之中
He's a--he's a fighter. He's pulling through.
莱姬在结肠切除后还有出血
Reggie had some oozing after his colon resection,
我们给它包扎后  情况就稳定了
but we packed it,and he's been stable ever since.
帕迪差点因出血过多而死
Uh, Paddy almost bled out
它的颈动脉被切断了
because his carotid was sliced right through,
我们做了搭接  它的情况也稳定了
but we put in a graft,and he's been stable ever since.
它现在完整如初
He's good as new.
很好
That's good.
大伙儿都干得很不错
That's great work,all of you.
把它们拿出去
So, uh, put them out
别忘了把详细过程记下来
and make sure that you write up all your work.
你说  拿出去  是什么意思
What do you mean,"Put them out"?
了结了它们  杀了这些猪
Terminate 'em. The pigs--kill 'em.
我不会杀这些猪的
I'm not killing those pigs.
我花了一整天才保住它们的命
I spent the entire day trying to keep them alive.
你要杀它们就自己动手
If you want them dead,you do it yourself.
你今天切除了半个肝脏
You resected half of a liver today.
你修复了隔膜  还做了脾切除术
You repaired a diaphragm and did a splenectomy.
你搭接了严重破损的动脉
You grafted a severed artery
你修复了破损的膀胱
And repaired a lacerated bladder,
完成了叶切除术
performed a lobectomy.
我知道你还取出了一个肿瘤
and I understand you even removed a tumor.
帕迪的  在它的甲状腺附近
On Paddy. His thyroid.
你知不知道自己今天学到了多少
Do you have any idea how much you just learned?
它们会很痛苦的
They'd be in pain.
这些都是重伤  要数个月才能恢复
Those are massive injuries,months of recovery.
经历了这么多  还让它们活着受罪
To keep them alive after all that,
这样太不人道了
That's not humane.
你真的不记得我了
Seriously,you don't remember my name?
我记得你  但那是从前
I remember your name,but that was before.
上次的任务  我参加了一个战地手术团队
This last tour, I was on a forward surgical team.
我们
We, uh...
在战地里给伤员治疗
treated combat casualties in the field.
脑子里只是想着如何控制伤势
You're mostly just looking to do damage control--
给他们止痛  开气孔
sedate 'em, ventilate 'em,
把他们空运到巴格达  然后离开
airlift 'em to Baghdad,then get outta there.
但这次  我们走得不够快
Only this one time,we didn't get out fast enough
我们遭到了导弹的攻击
because we ended up in the middle of an R.P.G. ambush.
包括我在内共20人的队伍里
There were 20 people in my unit, including me,
死了19个
and 19 died.
我也被卸职了
And then I got discharged.
所以  我不再是以前的我了
So... I'm not there anymore, in the before.
过去的我知道你的名字
I knew your name in the before.
可我走出过去了
But now I'm living in the after.
爱瑞
Erica--
你想道歉的话  去找贝利
You want to apologize to someone, apologize to Bailey.
多亏了你  我今天跟贝利对着干了一天
Thanks to you, I made her life a living hell today.
我跟马克·斯隆睡过
I slept with Mark Sloan.
你就这么道歉的  你真是
If that's your idea of an apology, you seriously--
你给我闭嘴
Shut up.
你  你早上哭成那样
You--you were--you were crying
还看见树叶
and--and--and seeing leaves.
可我没有
And I wasn't.
我也许永远都  看不见树叶
Okay? I-I may never see leaves.
也许我能看见树叶  还能看见花
Or--or maybe I will see leaves,but I will also see flowers.
我也许是个狂野的女孩  我不确定
I might be a whole forest girl.I don't know yet.
但我知道我想跟你在一起
But I-I do know that I want to be with you,
因此我至少得告诉你真相
And to do that, I have to at least tell you the truth,
真相就是  我今天跟马克·斯隆睡过
and the truth is,I slept with Mark Sloan today.
好吧
Okay.
而且是两次
Twice, actually.
好吧
Okay.
你呼我
You paged?
是的  托瑞怎么样了
Yeah, um, yeah. How's Tori?
她很好  很稳定
Oh, she's good. Stable.
你刚才不是错觉
You weren't imagining things.
你小时候总是抱着娃娃跑来跑去
You used to run around here with that doll all the time.
到哪里都带着她
Took her everywhere--
餐厅  手术观察室
The cafeteria,the O.R. Gallery.
托瑞有一大家人做后盾
Tori's got a whole army.
你却一个都没有
You didn't have anyone.
看着解剖娃娃简
Seeing anatomy Jane...
让我为此非常自责
reminded me of how much I was to blame for that.
你时刻提醒着我自己这一生有多失败
You're a living reminder of every failure in my life.
这不是你的错
That's not your fault.
如果一句对不起
And if I thought I'm sorry
能让你好受些
would hold any meaning for you at all,
我一定会说
I would say it.
我可以每天说上几百遍
I'd say it a thousand times a day.
有些战争永远不会结束
Some wars are never over.
有些停息得很艰难
Some end in an uneasy truce.
我做不到
I can't do it.
我知道我该这么做  可是
I know I'm supposed to,but...
它们会很痛苦
They'll suffer.
别让它们痛苦下去
Don't let them suffer.
值班室的游戏结束了
So no more on call room, huh?
恐怕是的
Afraid not.
这太糟了
That's, uh,that's too bad.
那就  明天见
I guess I'll, uh, see you around.
你想喝点什么吗
You wanna get a drink?
你说真的
Really?
我们不再做爱了
Just because we're not sleeping together
不代表我们不能去玩  我们还是朋友
doesn't mean we can't hang out, be friends.
你的优点不只是擅长做爱而已  马克
You're good for more than sex, Mark.
我很愿意去喝一杯
I would love to get a drink.
她不会每次都哭的是吧
She's not gonna cry every time, right?
不会的  已经过去了
No, no, no. That passes.
有的战争
Some wars result...
则是以完美胜利而收场
in complete and total victory.
坐下
Sit.
芝士通心粉
Um, mac and cheese--
自己做的  不是冷冻食品
From the box,not the freezer.
有的战争因一方妥协而终止
Some wars end with a peace offering.
我今天给猪取了名字
I named the pigs today.
不好意思  你想说什么
I'm sorry, but I don't know what that means.
我太在意自己了
I take things personally.
我太情绪化了
I get too emotional.
工作中不可以这样
There's no place for it at work,
对猪不行  对你也不行
Not--not with the pigs and not with you.
对不起
I'm sorry.
这比冷冻的那种好吃多了
This is so much better than the freezer kind.
我以为你今晚在米雪那过夜
I thought you were sleeping with Michelle tonight.
或者是杰克家
Or was it Jackie?
伊兹
Iz--
我今天一整天都很糟  阿历克斯  还有一晚上
I've had a hard day, Alex,and a sad night.
-你能不能让我单独待会儿  -伊兹
- So can you please just leave me alone?  - Izzie--
-怎么  -我不擅长这样  好吗
- What?  - I'm not good at this,all right?
我不擅长处理人际关系
I'm not good at--at relationships
或是谈论无趣的内心感受
or talking about stupid feelings,
而你擅长
And... And you are,
也许你能教教我
So maybe you could teach me or something, you know?
告诉我做错了什么
Tell me what I did wrong.
你不想我们去约会别人
You don't want us to see other people.
You don't want us to see other people,
你居然通过这种方法来告诉我
and that's how you tried to tell me...
问我是否同意
by asking if it was cool
你跟米雪搞
if you screwed Michelle.
你再笑我就走了
Laughing is not helping.
对不起  对不起
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
你想我教你是吗
So you want lessons, huh?
是的
I want lessons.
那好吧
Mm-hmm. Okay.
那就先开始说  伊泽贝尔·斯蒂文斯
You start with,Isobel Stevens,
你的床上功夫太棒了
You are staggeringly good in bed.
你很聪明  很可爱
You're amazing smart,wonderfully funny.
你还很爱护动物
and you care about animals.
就从这个开始
That's where I start?
是的  然后你再说你想跟我确立恋爱关系
Yeah. And then you say,you want to go steady with me?
几十年前的人才这么说
That's what I would say if it was 1952.
阿历克斯
Alex.
你想跟我确立恋爱关系吗
You wanna go steady with me?
如果你想要的话
Mm, if that's what you want.
行  我随便
I mean, yeah, whatever.
而有些战争
And some wars...
因希望而止息
end in hope.
瞧
Oh, look.
我小学时天天都戴这个上学
I wore this every day to elementary school.
很好看  你母亲给你织的
Nice. Your mom make that for you?
是的  也许是她
Yeah, right. She probably got it
在医院的失物招领处找回来的
at the lost and found at the hospital.
梅  你该来看看这个
Mer, you should do this one.
又找到小帽子了
Is it more ugly hats?
又一本日记
Another diary?
不止一本
More than one.
但这些战争都不算什么
But all these wars are nothing...
天哪
Oh, god.
最可怕的战争
Compared to the most frightening war of all...
是你即将面对的战争
the one you have yet to fight.